<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Qinghao (Leo) Liang</title>
    <link>//qinghaoliang.github.io/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Qinghao (Leo) Liang</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>qinghao.liang@yale.edu (Qinghao Liang)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>qinghao.liang@yale.edu (Qinghao Liang)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2024 22:10:16 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//qinghaoliang.github.io/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Learning brain phenotype relationship across atlases</title>
      <link>//qinghaoliang.github.io/projects/learning_across_atlases/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2024 22:10:16 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>qinghao.liang@yale.edu (Qinghao Liang)</author>
      <guid>//qinghaoliang.github.io/projects/learning_across_atlases/</guid>
      <description>Data heterogeneity, notably due to variations in brain atlases, poses a significant challenge in federated learning (FL) and meta-learning within neuroimaging, especially in functional MRI (fMRI) studies of neurological diseases. The diversity of brain atlases leads to inconsistencies in data representation, complicating the aggregation of insights across different datasets in a federated learning framework. This heterogeneity affects the collaborative training of models, as it introduces variability in data distributions and model architectures across institutions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rescuing missing data with imputation in connectome-based predictive modeling</title>
      <link>//qinghaoliang.github.io/projects/missing_data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 16:10:19 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>qinghao.liang@yale.edu (Qinghao Liang)</author>
      <guid>//qinghaoliang.github.io/projects/missing_data/</guid>
      <description>Our manuscript is published at Imaging Neuroscience https://direct.mit.edu/imag/article/doi/10.1162/imag_a_00071/118937
Connectome-based Predictive modeling Figure 1. Flowchart of Connectome-based Predictive modeling in neuroimage analysis.
Connectome-based Predictive Modeling (CPM) is a technique in neuroscience that predicts individual behaviors, cognitive abilities, and disease states from brain connectivity patterns. The neuroimaging data is first preprocessing and parcelated using brain atlas. Connectome is then generated by the correlaiton of average functional Magnetic resonance imaging (fMRI) timeseries between nodes or tracking the white matter fibers in Diffusion Tensor Imaging (DTI).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resolving Atlas Divergence in Connectomes: A Lightweight Domain Adaptation Approach Using Optimal Transport</title>
      <link>//qinghaoliang.github.io/projects/connectome_transformation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 15:35:51 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>qinghao.liang@yale.edu (Qinghao Liang)</author>
      <guid>//qinghaoliang.github.io/projects/connectome_transformation/</guid>
      <description>Our manuscript is published at International Workshop on Graphs in Biomedical Image Analysis, MICCAI 2022 https://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-3-031-21083-9_12
In neuroimaging research, sharing open datasets boosts transparency, reproducibility, and cross-disciplinary work, advancing our understanding of brain functions. Yet, the diversity in brain atlas standards complicates data sharing and connectome comparability. Innovative domain adaptation techniques, like entropic Gromov-Wasserstein distance and optimal transport with matrix factorization, help overcome these challenges by enabling the mapping of connectomes across different atlas spaces.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
